<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Welcome on ChrisK91.me</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/</link><description>Recent content in Welcome on ChrisK91.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisk91.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>about me</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/pages/about/</guid><description>Throughout my youth, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a keen interest in computer sciences and technology. Starting with basic markup, I started creating basic websites early on. This lead me to &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; languages not much later. After trying to pick up C++ as a client side language, I soon returned to web. With some friends we decided to take out schools parent conference day registration to the web. During the years I became proficient in web and worked on numerous side projects and small proof-of-concepts.</description></item><item><title>Moving to Hugo</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2023-03-06-Moving-to-Hugo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2023-03-06-Moving-to-Hugo/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always liked static site generators for my homepages, as they offer a variety of advantages for me. By nature, blog posts are updated very rarely. Static pages are easy to archive or download &amp;ndash; for instance you can find the earliest snapshot from 2018 working via the wayback machine here. All modern static site engines allow for writing in Markdown, making it easy for me to add posts.
In the past, I used Jekyll as my go-to, recently however I moved to Hugo.</description></item><item><title>My collection of medical calculators and checklists - medist.org</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2021-08-12-Medical-checklists/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2021-08-12-Medical-checklists/</guid><description>With my graduation last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve started a page, to create a tidied collection of my current notes. As with my personal page, it is based on Hugo, which I find a bit more flexible to work with in comparison to Jekyll. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the technical stuff, this post is for you!</description></item><item><title>My second homepage</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2020-02-20-A-second-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2020-02-20-A-second-home/</guid><description>With my adventures into landscape photography, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a second homepage for my new hobby. Here are some technical aspects about the site, which you can find at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->christian-j.com&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Camera Transfer - Remote capturing and file transfer for Canon camera and Window 10</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2019-04-05-EOS-Transfer-CCAPI-App-For-Windows-10/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2019-04-05-EOS-Transfer-CCAPI-App-For-Windows-10/</guid><description>I recently got a new Canon camera, and was missing a simple app to transfer files to my Windows 10 devices. So I created one!</description></item><item><title>ECG Visualizer</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-10-05-ECG-Visualizer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-10-05-ECG-Visualizer/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve created a small webapp to visualize, how the angle of the main electrical axis influences the three main leads I, II and III.</description></item><item><title>Anki Templates - An introduction to HTML</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-09-28-Anki-Templates-Introduction-HTML/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-09-28-Anki-Templates-Introduction-HTML/</guid><description>Anki utilizes HTML in its template engine. HTML is quite easy to pick up, and a basic understanding will get you started in improving your Anki templates right away!</description></item><item><title>Basic CSS-Template for Anki</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-09-19-Basic-CSS-Template-for-Anki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-09-19-Basic-CSS-Template-for-Anki/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to create a &amp;ldquo;base&amp;rdquo;-style for Anki. Several elements (for instance lists) don&amp;rsquo;t look that great in Anki, and I have created a small CSS to rectify that.</description></item><item><title>Pagination with Jekyll and Foundation Sites 6</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-09-09-Pagination-with-Jekyll-and-Foundation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-09-09-Pagination-with-Jekyll-and-Foundation/</guid><description>Prerequisites This post assumes, that you already have a site running. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to run bundle update, to get your dependencies up to date. I will utilize the Jekyll pagination plugin which is available on GitHub pages, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to build your site locally.
Important: the plugin only works when your posts are listed on your index.html page, this is a restriction of GitHub pages, which bundles jekyll-paginate in version 1.</description></item><item><title>Adding Hints in Anki</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-04-28-Adding-Hint-fields-in-Anki/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-04-28-Adding-Hint-fields-in-Anki/</guid><description>Ever wondered how you can add a hint in Anki, for the time when you just can&amp;rsquo;t remember an answer? It&amp;rsquo;s rather simple with some basic CSS and JavaScript</description></item><item><title>Building Anki 2.1 on Windows 10</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-04-18-Building-Anki-2.1-on-Windows-10/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-04-18-Building-Anki-2.1-on-Windows-10/</guid><description>Anki 2.1 is the upcoming version of the popular spaced repetition software. If you want to write plugins, you might want to have the option to run Anki 2.1 from source for debugging purposes. Here I will outline, how I set up my system to build and run Anki from source.</description></item><item><title>CSS in Anki — Beyond the basics</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-02-17-CSS-in-Anki-Beyond-basic-use/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-02-17-CSS-in-Anki-Beyond-basic-use/</guid><description>You can style your cards in Anki with CSS, that&amp;rsquo;s nothing new. But we can also use some not so obvious CSS to add visual cues to help us remember stuff on our cards.</description></item><item><title>Setting up VSCode for Anki add on development.</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-02-13-Setting-up-VSCode-for-Anki-addon-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-02-13-Setting-up-VSCode-for-Anki-addon-development/</guid><description>VSCode has become a powerful editor for Python. Here I share my setup, to develop Anki addons using VSCode.</description></item><item><title>Accessing the Anki database from R</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-02-03-Accessing-the-Anki-database-via-R/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2018-02-03-Accessing-the-Anki-database-via-R/</guid><description>Anki uses a SQLite database to keep track of your reviews and cards. I always wanted to use R to create some graphs and visualize my learning process. Here is some code, to get you started as well!</description></item><item><title>Sharing CSS across multiple cards in Anki</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2017-12-20-Sharing-CSS-across-multiple-cards-in-Anki/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2017-12-20-Sharing-CSS-across-multiple-cards-in-Anki/</guid><description>Tired of copying and pasting various CSS snippets across multiple cards? By using the CSS &lt;code>@include&lt;/code>, you can share the same CSS file across multiple cards.</description></item><item><title>Pixels</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-10-30-Pixels/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-10-30-Pixels/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ll most likely have a general idea of a &amp;ldquo;pixel&amp;rdquo;. But what happens to a pixel when we try to scale up a complete image? Do we get a big pixel? And what size does a pixel have? We will have a basic look and try to get a more accurate idea of pixels. We will also learn, that some manipulations are required in order to magnify or rotate pictures.</description></item><item><title>Bit depths, image data and histograms</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-10-09-Bit-depth/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-10-09-Bit-depth/</guid><description>Have you ever seen a dialog, asking you for a bit depth when saving an image? Here we will take a short stroll into the storage of image information and see, how a computer needs to transform information in order to store it on disc. We will talk about artifacts and problems that could arise, if no appropriate bit depth is chosen. Finally, we will check out histograms to assess the quality of an image.</description></item><item><title>Hands on — Color models and ImageJ</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-10-05-Hands-on-Color-models-and-ImageJ/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-10-05-Hands-on-Color-models-and-ImageJ/</guid><description>Often times you are interested in features of a certain color. We will look at how to extract the different aspects of color models in ImageJ and see how we can use the Color Threshold option to select features based on their visual appearance.</description></item><item><title>An introduction to color</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-09-28-An-introduction-to-color/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/post/2016-09-28-An-introduction-to-color/</guid><description>When you start working with digital images, some fundamentals should be known. Here we will take a look at color spaces and models &amp;mdash; ways to represent and break up the &amp;ldquo;contents&amp;rdquo; of a color. This knowledge can come in handy, when you want to do automatic feature detection in an image. Maybe you are interested in red precipitates or want to distinguish a purple cell from a green one? Or maybe you are just interested in some basics about images without complicated formulas.</description></item><item><title>correlation shift</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/tools/correlation-shift.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/tools/correlation-shift.html</guid><description>You can use this tool to maximize the correlation of two images. This can be useful if you experience a certain shift when switching channels. The program calculates the Pearson Product-Moment coefficient and determines to offset where it reaches its maximum. Especially if features are present with the same intensity in both channels, they tend to be aligned very well.
Download
Select x64 (64bit) or x86 (32bit) depending on your architecture</description></item><item><title>Privacy policy for Camera Connect</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_connect_privacy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_connect_privacy.html</guid><description>English version below
Die App teilt keine Inhalte mit Drittanbietern. Bei einem Absturz werden ggf. Informationen gesammelt, die mit Google geteilt werden.
Zugriff auf das lokale Netzwerk ist für die Verbindung mit der Kamera notwending. Zugriff auf Bibliotheken ist zum Speichern von Bildern nötig.
This app doesn&amp;rsquo;t share information with third parties. In case of a crash, inforations might be collected by Google.
Access to your local network is requires to connect to your camera.</description></item><item><title>Privacy policy for Camera Transfer</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_transfer_privacy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_transfer_privacy.html</guid><description>English version below
Die App teilt keine Inhalte mit Drittanbietern. Bei einem Absturz werden Informationen gesammelt, und an Microsoft gesendet. Dies kann in den Einstellungen des Betriebssystems deaktiviert werden.
Zugriff auf das lokale Netzwerk ist für die Verbindung mit der Kamera notwending. Zugriff auf Bibliotheken ist zum Speichern von Bildern nötig.
This app doesn&amp;rsquo;t share information with third parties. In case of a crash, some infromation is gathered and collected by Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>