<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on ChrisK91.me</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on ChrisK91.me</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://chrisk91.me/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>about me</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/pages/about/</guid><description>Throughout my youth, I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a keen interest in computer sciences and technology. Starting with basic markup, I started creating basic websites early on. This lead me to &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; languages not much later. After trying to pick up C++ as a client side language, I soon returned to web. With some friends we decided to take out schools parent conference day registration to the web. During the years I became proficient in web and worked on numerous side projects and small proof-of-concepts.</description></item><item><title>correlation shift</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/tools/correlation-shift.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/tools/correlation-shift.html</guid><description>You can use this tool to maximize the correlation of two images. This can be useful if you experience a certain shift when switching channels. The program calculates the Pearson Product-Moment coefficient and determines to offset where it reaches its maximum. Especially if features are present with the same intensity in both channels, they tend to be aligned very well.
Download
Select x64 (64bit) or x86 (32bit) depending on your architecture</description></item><item><title>Privacy policy for Camera Connect</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_connect_privacy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_connect_privacy.html</guid><description>English version below
Die App teilt keine Inhalte mit Drittanbietern. Bei einem Absturz werden ggf. Informationen gesammelt, die mit Google geteilt werden.
Zugriff auf das lokale Netzwerk ist für die Verbindung mit der Kamera notwending. Zugriff auf Bibliotheken ist zum Speichern von Bildern nötig.
This app doesn&amp;rsquo;t share information with third parties. In case of a crash, inforations might be collected by Google.
Access to your local network is requires to connect to your camera.</description></item><item><title>Privacy policy for Camera Transfer</title><link>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_transfer_privacy.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chrisk91.me/pages/camera_transfer_privacy.html</guid><description>English version below
Die App teilt keine Inhalte mit Drittanbietern. Bei einem Absturz werden Informationen gesammelt, und an Microsoft gesendet. Dies kann in den Einstellungen des Betriebssystems deaktiviert werden.
Zugriff auf das lokale Netzwerk ist für die Verbindung mit der Kamera notwending. Zugriff auf Bibliotheken ist zum Speichern von Bildern nötig.
This app doesn&amp;rsquo;t share information with third parties. In case of a crash, some infromation is gathered and collected by Microsoft.</description></item></channel></rss>